overcomingbias.com 2016-11-07

# Overcoming Bias : Privacy Policy

## Overview & Disclaimers

The blog publisher values the privacy of his site visitors. Any of the following personal information that may be made available to the blog publisher when browsing or navigating the site shall be kept confidential:

  * First and last name
  * Email address, and other similar information
  * Occupation 
    * Industry
    * Personal interests
    * Any other information needed to provide a service you requested

Examples of scenarios where visitors provide their personal information include, but may not be limited, to:

  * Participating in an online survey.
  * Requesting inclusion in an email or other mailing list.
  * Logging in to the site, thus requiring a user name and/or a password.

The blog publisher provides you the opportunity to agree or decline to give your personal information via the Internet. He will inform you of the purpose for the collection and does not intend to transfer your personal information to third parties without your consent, except under the limited conditions described under the discussion entitled “Information Sharing and Disclosure” below. If you choose to provide the blog publisher with your personal information, he may transfer that information to a third-party service provider as necessary.

### Domain Information Collection

The blog publisher may collect domain information to enable him to analyze how visitors use this site. This data enables him to become more familiar with which people visit the site, how often they visit, and what parts of the site they visit most often. The blog publisher uses this information to improve his Web-based offerings. This information is collected automatically and requires no action on your part.

### Use of Cookies and Tracking User Traffic

Some pages on this site may use “cookies” — small files that the site places on your hard drive for identification purposes. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID to track the pages visited, but the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. These files are used for site registration and customization the next time you visit us.

Some parts of the site may also use cookies to track user traffic patterns. The blog publisher does this in order to determine the usefulness of our Web site information to users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information. Please note that cookies cannot read data off of your hard drive. Your Web browser may allow you to be notified when you are receiving a cookie, giving you the choice to accept it or not.

If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our Web site, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, By not accepting cookies, some pages may not fully function and you may not be able to access certain information on this site.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Your personal information is never shared without your permission, except under the condition listed below:

  * if required to do so by law, or in urgent circumstances, to protect personal safety, the public or the site.

### Internet Security

The blog publisher strives to protect your personal information; however, he urges you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. Change your passwords often, use a combination of letters.

### Protecting Children

Children under 13 years old are not the target audience for this site. Some topics discussed on this site may not be generally considered suitable for children.

### Links to Third Party Sites

This site may contain links to other sites. The blog publisher does not share your personal information with those Web sites and is not responsible for their privacy practices. He encourages you to learn about the privacy policies of those companies.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

The blog publisher reserves the right to change, modify or update this policy at any time without notice. Any substantial changes in the way he uses your personal information will be posted on this site. If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please email the webmaster at the contact information on the site.
